SamuelBrandão

Software Engineer

contact

Via Ruggero Leoncavallo, 10 Milan, 20131 - Italy

+39 3894570300

gb.samuel@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/sambrandao github.com/khamusa bitbucket.org/khamusa

languages

portuguese native english fluency italian fluency

programming Pvthon 3

♥ Ruby (& Rails)
PostgreSQL, MySQL
MongoDB
Git
C
JavaScript
Angular, JQuery
CSS3 & HTML5
F#
Erlang
Scala
Java

concepts

PHP & Wordpress

♥ Functional Programming
 ♥ Software Design
 ♥ Agile development
 ♥ BDD Workflows
 Database Design
 MetaProgramming
 Maintainability

summary

Accomplished software engineer with 7+ years of experience building products (SaaS) using a range of technologies including Ruby/Rails, Python and JavaScript with multiple frameworks, relational and NoSQL databases.

experience

apr/2015-Now

Senior Developer at 77Agency

http://www.allin1social.com, Italy

- Main Developer on Allin1social
- ♦ Performed extensive bugfixing, reduced the legacy code complexity, improved code design and quality according to every measurable metric.
- ♦ Reduced the time spent by support staff by creating tools that brought to surface the most critical issues affecting the clients experience.
- ♦ Improved the data retrieval, integration and processing mechanism, both by optimizing existing tasks and also by applying advanced heuristics, which led to an 82% reduction of the overall daily/hourly workload, and a considerable service reliability boost.
- ◆ Main technologies used: Ruby / Rails, MongoDB, Redis, JS / ReactJS.

2004-apr/2015 **F**

Freelance Developer

Brazil, Italy

Developer

Worked as a Freelance Developer since 2004, having worked with a coprehensive set of technologies, including Ruby, Python, PHP (using Codelgniter, Wordpress, Magento), JS/CoffeeScript, AngularJs and ReactJs.

particular projects

2012-2014

Miviro

http://www.miviro.com.br

Lead Developer

Miviro is a social network/management tool for tour agencies, developed with Ruby on Rails, HTML5, CSS3 and plenty of Javascript/Ajax. Implementation of new features, database and application redesign. Implemented a natural guery interface to the database.

2011 Wertix CMS

Standalone project

Lead Developer

Wertix was a Content Management System developed from scratch as a mean to practice and learn the Ruby on Rails framework. The resulting application was surprisingly easy to use, leading many of my clients to migrate to it.

education

2011-2015

Bachelor of Computer Science, graduated *cum laude* Laurea in Informatica

Università degli Studi di Milano

about me

I started programming at the age of 11 and working professionaly at the age of 19. While being a self-taught programmer contributed significantly to my problem solving skills, I decided to pursue a more conscious and comprehensive knowledge of the computing ecosystem, enrolling for a Bachelor Degree in Milan/Italy, which I completed *cum laude* in april 2015. I've also worked as a professional (theater) actor in Brazil, for more than 5 years! As a result, I love speaking in public, presenting ideas, products or projects. My ideal work scenario is a team-based product-centered development environment.